<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS11055</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-05-15T23:48:12Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-16T09:18:12+09:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-05-15T23:48:12Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-05-16T23:48:12Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-19T23:59:59+09:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-05-16T06:25:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-16T15:55:00+09:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FDS</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region"/>
        <area aac="SA_PW015" description="Mount Lofty Ranges" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, becoming less likely in the late afternoon and evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds northwesterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures between 18 and 21.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:10am to 1:00pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the late morning and afternoon. Light winds. Overnight temperatures falling to around 12 with daytime temperatures reaching between 17 and 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the evening. Light winds becoming westerly 15 to 20 km/h during the afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to around 9 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Winds west to northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h turning southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning. Overnight temperatures falling to between 9 and 12 with daytime temperatures reaching between 16 and 19.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW002" description="Yorke Peninsula" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds northwesterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures in the low 20s.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:20am to 1:00pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the late morning and afternoon. Light winds becoming south to southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h in the early afternoon then becoming light in the late afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to around 12 with daytime temperatures reaching the low 20s.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the evening. Light winds becoming west to southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h during the day. Overnight temperatures falling to around 10 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Winds westerly 15 to 20 km/h turning southwesterly 20 to 30 km/h during the morning. Overnight temperatures falling to between 9 and 12 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW003" description="Kangaroo Island" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers, becoming less likely in the late afternoon and evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the late morning and afternoon. Winds northwesterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures around 20.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 12:30pm to 1:30pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the late morning and afternoon. Light winds. Overnight temperatures falling to around 11 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. High chance of showers, most likely in the afternoon and evening. Light winds becoming northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h during the morning then tending westerly 15 to 25 km/h during the day. Overnight temperatures falling to around 8 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers. Winds west to southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h. Overnight temperatures falling to between 9 and 12 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW004" description="Upper South East" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. Very high chance of showers, becoming less likely in the evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds northerly 20 to 30 km/h becoming light in the late afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures between 18 and 21.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection not recommended, UV Index predicted to reach 2 [Low]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. The chance of a thunderstorm in the morning and afternoon. The chance of morning fog. Light winds becoming southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h in the early afternoon then becoming light in the late afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to around 11 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower, most likely in the evening. Light winds becoming westerly 15 to 20 km/h during the day then becoming light during the afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to around 9 with daytime temperatures reaching around 19.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers. Winds west to northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h tending west to southwesterly 20 to 30 km/h during the morning. Overnight temperatures falling to between 7 and 10 with daytime temperatures reaching around 19.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW005" description="Lower South East" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. Very high chance of rain, becoming less likely in the late afternoon and evening. The chance of a thunderstorm near the coast in the afternoon. Winds northerly 20 to 30 km/h becoming light in the late afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures around 18.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection not recommended, UV Index predicted to reach 2 [Low]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. The chance of morning fog in the north. Light winds becoming southerly 15 to 20 km/h in the middle of the day then becoming light in the late afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to around 11 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the evening. Light winds becoming west to northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h during the afternoon then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 8 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers. Winds west to northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h tending west to southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning. Overnight temperatures falling to around 9 with daytime temperatures reaching around 18.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW006" description="Riverland" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. Very high chance of showers. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds north to northeasterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light in the evening. Daytime maximum temperatures between 18 and 22.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:10am to 1:00pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. Medium chance of showers. The chance of a thunderstorm in the morning and afternoon. The chance of morning fog. Light winds. Overnight temperatures falling to around 10 with daytime temperatures reaching the low 20s.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds. Overnight temperatures falling to around 9 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Light winds becoming westerly 15 to 20 km/h during the morning then tending southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the day. Overnight temperatures falling to around 6 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW007" description="Murraylands" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. High chance of showers, becoming less likely in the evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds northerly 20 to 30 km/h becoming light in the late afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures between 18 and 21.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:30am to 12:40pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. The chance of a thunderstorm in the early morning. The chance of morning fog. Light winds. Overnight temperatures falling to around 11 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds becoming southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h during the afternoon then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 9 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Winds westerly 15 to 25 km/h tending southwesterly during the day then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 8 with daytime temperatures reaching around 19.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW008" description="Mid North" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers, becoming less likely in the evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds northerly 15 to 25 km/h tending northwesterly in the middle of the day then becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures between 19 and 23.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:10am to 1:10pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers. Light winds becoming south to southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h in the early afternoon then becoming light in the late afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to between 8 and 11 with daytime temperatures reaching between 18 and 21.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds becoming southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h during the day then becoming light during the afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to between 6 and 9 with daytime temperatures reaching between 17 and 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Winds west to southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 6 and 9 with daytime temperatures reaching between 15 and 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW009" description="Flinders" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. High chance of showers. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening, possibly severe with damaging winds, large hail and heavy rain which may lead to flash flooding west of the ranges. Winds northerly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures between 18 and 22.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 10:50am to 1:40pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. The chance of a thunderstorm in the morning and afternoon. Light winds becoming south to southeasterly 15 to 20 km/h in the morning then becoming light in the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 8 and 13 with daytime temperatures reaching between 18 and 21.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds becoming south to southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the day then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 6 and 11 with daytime temperatures reaching around 19.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog west of the ranges. Slight chance of a shower south of Hawker, near zero chance elsewhere. Winds southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 5 and 9 with daytime temperatures reaching between 16 and 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW010" description="West Coast" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the afternoon and evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds north to northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h shifting southerly 15 to 25 km/h in the late morning and afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures in the low to mid 20s.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:10am to 1:50pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds becoming southerly 15 to 20 km/h in the early afternoon then becoming light in the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 10 with daytime temperatures reaching the low 20s.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds becoming southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the day then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 8 with daytime temperatures reaching between 19 and 22.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers south of Streaky Bay, slight chance elsewhere. Winds west to northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h turning southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 7 and 10 with daytime temperatures reaching between 19 and 22.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW011" description="Eastern Eyre Peninsula" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers, most likely in the afternoon and evening. A thunderstorm likely in the afternoon and evening, possibly severe with damaging winds, large hail and heavy rain which may lead to flash flooding. Winds northerly 15 to 20 km/h tending northwesterly 15 to 25 km/h in the morning then becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures in the low 20s.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:10am to 1:20pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower, most likely in the late morning and afternoon. Light winds becoming southerly 15 to 20 km/h in the early afternoon then becoming light in the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 11 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower. Light winds becoming west to southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h during the day then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 8 and 11 with daytime temperatures reaching between 18 and 21.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Light winds becoming westerly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning then tending southwesterly during the day. Overnight temperatures falling to around 10 with daytime temperatures reaching between 18 and 21.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW012" description="Lower Eyre Peninsula" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the afternoon and evening. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening. Winds northwesterly 15 to 20 km/h tending westerly in the middle of the day then becoming light in the early afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures in the low 20s.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 11:30am to 1:00pm, UV Index predicted to reach 3 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the late morning and afternoon. Light winds becoming southeast to southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h in the middle of the day then becoming light in the late afternoon. Overnight temperatures falling to around 10 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the evening. Light winds becoming westerly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to around 8 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. Medium chance of showers, most likely in the morning and afternoon. Winds westerly 15 to 20 km/h tending southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 9 and 12 with daytime temperatures reaching around 20.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW013" description="North West Pastoral" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. High chance of showers east of Coober Pedy, slight chance elsewhere. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening, possibly severe with damaging winds, large hail and heavy rain which may lead to flash flooding east of Coober Pedy. Winds northwest to northeasterly 15 to 25 km/h tending northwest to southwesterly 15 to 20 km/h in the middle of the day then tending southeast to southwesterly in the late afternoon. Daytime maximum temperatures in the low to high 20s.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 10:30am to 2:20pm, UV Index predicted to reach 4 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog south of Coober Pedy. Slight chance of a shower north of Coober Pedy, most likely in the afternoon and evening. Near zero chance of rain elsewhere. The chance of a thunderstorm in the late afternoon and evening. Winds south to southeasterly 15 to 20 km/h becoming light in the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 10 and 14 with daytime temperatures reaching the low to mid 20s.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">The chance of morning fog. Mostly sunny afternoon. Winds south to southeasterly 15 to 20 km/h tending south to southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the day then tending south to southeasterly 15 to 20 km/h during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 8 and 11 with daytime temperatures reaching the low 20s.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Mostly sunny. The chance of morning fog south of Coober Pedy. Slight chance of a shower south of Woomera, near zero chance elsewhere. Light winds becoming southeast to southwesterly 15 to 25 km/h during the morning then becoming light during the evening. Overnight temperatures falling to between 6 and 9 with daytime temperatures reaching the low 20s.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
        <area aac="SA_PW014" description="North East Pastoral" type="public-district" parent-aac="SA_FA001">
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. Very high chance of rain east of Leigh Creek, high chance elsewhere. The chance of a thunderstorm in the afternoon and evening, possibly severe with damaging winds, large hail and heavy rain which may lead to flash flooding west of Leigh Creek. Winds north to northeasterly 15 to 25 km/h becoming light in the evening. Daytime maximum temperatures between 19 and 25.</text>
                <text type="uv_alert">Sun protection 10:20am to 2:00pm, UV Index predicted to reach 4 [Moderate]</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Cloudy. Very high chance of showers in the far northeast, medium chance elsewhere. The chance of a thunderstorm. The chance of morning fog. Light winds becoming south to southeasterly 15 to 25 km/h in the morning. Overnight temperatures falling to between 10 and 16 with daytime temperatures reaching between 19 and 22.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Partly cloudy. The chance of morning fog. Slight chance of a shower east of Leigh Creek in the morning and afternoon. Near zero chance of rain elsewhere. Winds southerly 20 to 30 km/h. Overnight temperatures falling to between 9 and 15 with daytime temperatures reaching between 19 and 23.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Mostly sunny. The chance of morning fog south of Yunta. Slight chance of a shower south of Yunta, most likely in the afternoon. Near zero chance of rain elsewhere. Winds southerly 15 to 25 km/h. Overnight temperatures falling to between 7 and 12 with daytime temperatures reaching between 19 and 22.</text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
