<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-03-30T05:30:00Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-30T16:00:00+10:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-03-30T05:30:04Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-03-30T20:30:00Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-30T16:00:05+10:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CDT">2026-04-03T23:59:59+10:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-03-30T17:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-31T04:00:00+10:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-03-30T16:00:05+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-30T16:00:05+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-30T05:30:05Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-30T05:30:05Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A high pressure system over the Tasman sea extends a weak ridge over SA. A trough over central WA extends over southwest SA, and is forecast to move across the west and south later Tuesday, pushing into the northeast of SA on Wednesday. Another high pressure system is expected to become established south of the Bight late in the week.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-03-31T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-04-01T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-30T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-31T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers and thunderstorms in the far west, extending across the west during the day, reaching central districts at night. Thunderstorms possibly severe about the west during the afternoon and evening. Maximum temperatures above average, grading to slight below average in the far northeast. Northerly winds, freshening in the west ahead of a southwesterly change extending over western parts in the afternoon and evening, reaching central parts at night.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-03-30T17:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-31T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-30T06:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-30T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Dry apart from isolated showers and thunderstorms about the west. Generally northeast to northerly winds, southeast to northeasterly in the far northeast.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-04-01T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-04-02T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-31T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-04-01T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers and thunderstorms moving across the agricultural area and North West Pastoral district during the morning. Isolated showers to follow about coastal parts mostly clearing later. Maximum temperatures above average, lowering to slightly below average in the west. Northerly winds in the northeast, with southwest to southerly winds extending throughout during the day.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-04-02T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-04-03T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-04-01T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-04-02T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Dry apart from possible isolated showers about the southern coasts and possible showers in the northwest. Areas of morning fog about the agricultural area. Maximum temperatures near to slightly below average about the southern agricultural area, grading to above average in the north and east. Southwest to southeasterly winds and locally fresh afternoon sea breezes. Northwest to southwesterly winds in the southeast.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="4" start-time-local="2026-04-03T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-04-04T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-04-02T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-04-03T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Dry apart from isolated showers about the southern agricultural area and far southwest, clearing during the afternoon. Areas of morning fog about the agricultural area. Maximum temperatures slightly below average about the agricultural area, grading to above average in the north. South to southeasterly winds and locally fresh afternoon sea breezes.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Friday: Less than 2mm about the North West Pastoral district, agricultural areas and south of the North East Pastoral district, increasing to 2 to 5mm about western parts, with highly variable totals of 5 to 30 mm across the west from showers and thunderstorms Tuesday and into Wednesday.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
