<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-06-11T06:30:00Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-11T16:00:00+09:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-06-11T06:30:01Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-06-11T21:30:00Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-11T16:00:01+09:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-15T23:59:59+09:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-06-11T18:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-12T04:00:00+09:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-06-11T16:00:01+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-11T16:00:01+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-11T06:30:01Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-11T06:30:01Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A high pressure system in the Tasman Sea maintains a ridge over SA. A cold front will move across the Bight on Friday with a weak high pressure system developing over southern Australia over the weekend. A trough of low pressure moves into the far west on Monday as an associated low pressure system moves into the Bight.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-06-12T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-13T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-11T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-12T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers in the far west, tending to rain and extending over western coasts during the evening, possibly reaching Kangaroo Island late evening. Maximum temperatures above to well above average. Fresh and gusty northeast to northwesterly winds ahead of a west to southwesterly change moving across the far west late in the evening. Strong at times about the coast.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-06-11T17:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-12T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-11T07:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-11T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Isolated showers west of about Ceduna extending across the southern Eyre Peninsula and Kangaroo Island during the afternoon. Possible thunderstorms near western coasts. Maximum temperatures above average grading to well above average in the north. Generally northeasterly winds.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-06-13T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-14T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-12T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-13T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">A band of rain about the West Coast and far west moving across the agricultural area during the day and contracting to south of the pastorals and Flinders districts in the evening. Maximum temperatures near average grading to well above average in the northeast and below average about the far west. North to northwesterly winds ahead of a south to southwesterly change extending into the North East Pastoral district during the afternoon.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-06-14T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-15T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-13T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-14T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Isolated showers across the pastoral districts, becoming more frequent about the North West Pastoral during the day and extending into the West Coast during the evening. Morning fog patches on and east of the ranges. Possible thunderstorms about the far west later. Maximum temperatures near average grading to above average in the north and below average about the far west. Light winds tending southeast to northeasterly.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="4" start-time-local="2026-06-15T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-16T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-14T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-15T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Showers about the south of the North West Pastoral district and the West Coast, tending to patchy rain and extending into central and southeastern districts during the day. Possible thunderstorms about the west. Maximum temperatures near average grading to above average in the north. North to northeasterly winds ahead of a west to southwesterly change moving across the far west late in the evening.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Monday: mostly dry about the far north and northeast. 2 to 10 mm about the remaining parts of the pastoral districts and Flinders. Increasing to 10 to 20 mm about the West Coast and agricultural area. Isolated falls of 20 to 40 mm about the West Coast and Kangaroo Island.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
