<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-05-02T06:47:47Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-02T16:17:47+09:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-05-02T06:47:47Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-05-02T21:47:47Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-02T16:17:47+09:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-06T23:59:59+09:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-05-02T18:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-05-03T04:00:00+09:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-05-02T16:17:47+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-02T16:17:47+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-02T06:47:47Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-02T06:47:47Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A cold front over eastern districts will move to the east of SA overnight. The low pressure system associated with this front is expected to move slowly eastwards over waters to the south of the state and will extend a trough over southern parts of SA later Sunday and Monday. The low will then move over Bass Strait later Monday. A ridge will extend across SA from the west on Tuesday and a cold front will move across the south later Wednesday.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-05-03T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-04T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-02T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-03T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about the southern agricultural area and West Coast district and isolated light showers about the northern agricultural area. Chance of a thunderstorm near western and southern coasts. Patchy rain and isolated thunderstorms in the northeast contracting eastwards. Maximum temperatures generally below average. Fresh west to northwesterly winds in the south, becoming gusty at times near the coast. West to southwesterly winds in the north.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-05-02T17:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-03T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-02T07:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-02T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">A band of patchy rain and isolated gusty thunderstorms about central and and eastern parts, contracting eastwards during the evening. Isolated showers persisting about western and southern coasts. Fresh and gusty northerly winds ahead of a west to northwesterly change in the south, west to southwesterly in the north.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-05-04T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-05T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-03T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-04T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about the agricultural area and West Coast district, possibly extending into the south of the pastoral districts. Showers mostly contracting to coastal districts during the evening. Possible thunderstorms about the Murray and South East districts, clearing by early evening. Maximum temperatures below average. Southwesterly winds extending throughout, fresh and gusty at times near southern coasts.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-05-05T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-06T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-04T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-05T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Isolated showers about the agricultural area and West Coast district, becoming more frequent late afternoon and evening. Maximum temperatures below average. Southwest to southeasterly winds.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="4" start-time-local="2026-05-06T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-05-07T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-05-05T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-05-06T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Morning fog patches in the west. Isolated showers about the agricultural area and West Coast district, more frequent about the southern agricultural area. Maximum temperatures below average. Southwest to southeasterly winds turning northwesterly in the south ahead of a fresh and gusty southerly change late afternoon and evening.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Wednesday: 10 to 20 mm about the southern agricultural area, locally reaching 20 to 40 mm about the Mount Lofty Ranges, the Lower South East and western Kangaroo Island. 2 to 10 mm is expected over the remainder of the agricultural area and pastoral districts although local falls of 10 to 20 mm are possible in the northeast and near western coasts. Isolated higher falls are possible with thunderstorms.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
