<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-06-02T18:30:00Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-03T04:00:00+09:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-06-02T18:30:25Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-06-03T09:30:00Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-03T04:00:26+09:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-06T23:59:59+09:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-06-03T06:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-03T16:00:00+09:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-06-03T04:00:26+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-03T04:00:26+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-02T18:30:26Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-02T18:30:26Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A significant low pressure system west of TAS extends a trough over SA. A second weak low pressure system moves over waters to the south today extending a cold front over coastal parts later today into Thursday. A high pressure system develops over western and northern parts on Friday and a cold front embedded in the southwesterly flow clips the south.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-06-03T05:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-04T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-02T19:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-03T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about the West Coast and agricultural area, possibly reaching the south of the Pastoral districts. Possible thunderstorms developing near western coasts, Yorke Peninsula and Kangaroo Island during the late afternoon and evening. Maximum temperatures near average. Fresh and gusty westerly winds.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-06-04T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-05T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-03T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-04T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about the West Coast and agricultural area, possibly reaching the south of the Pastoral districts. Possible thunderstorms near central and eastern coastal parts. Maximum temperatures below average grading to slightly above average in the north. West to southwesterly winds, turning southwest to southerly during the day.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-06-05T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-06T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-04T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-05T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Isolated fog patches in the west. Showers about the west coast and agricultural areas, mainly about windward coasts and ranges. Maximum temperatures below average to near average. Southwest to southerly winds, shifting west to southwesterly about the agricultural area during the afternoon and evening.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-06-06T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-07T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-05T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-06T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Isolated fog patches in the west. Showers about the southern agricultural area, contracting to southern coasts during the afternoon and evening. Maximum temperatures slightly above average grading to below average in the far north. Southwest to southerly winds, shifting west to southwesterly about the agricultural area during the afternoon and evening.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Saturday: Less than 5 mm about the south of the Pastoral districts, increasing to 2 to 10 mm about the agricultural area, and to 10 to 25 mm about central windward coasts and ranges, with isolated falls in these areas of 25 to 40 mm.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
