<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-03-23T05:30:00Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-23T16:00:00+10:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-03-23T05:30:03Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-03-23T20:30:00Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-23T16:00:03+10:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-27T23:59:59+10:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-03-23T17:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CDT">2026-03-24T04:00:00+10:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-03-23T16:00:03+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-23T16:00:03+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-23T05:30:03Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-23T05:30:03Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A high pressure system over the Tasman sea, extends a ridge over southern SA. A broad trough moves over SA Tuesday, then a cold front clips the southeast as an upper trough moves up over SA Wednesday and Thursday. A new ridge develops south of the Bight late in the week.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-03-24T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-25T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-23T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-24T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Isolated showers about the agricultural area and south of the pastoral districts, mainly about the southeast. Possible thunderstorms about the southern agricultural area, mainly about the southeast. Maximum temperatures above average, grading to below average in the northeast. Northeast to northwesterly winds, shifting west to southwesterly in the south during the day. Local afternoon sea breezes.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-03-23T17:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-24T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-23T06:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-23T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Mostly dry. Possible isolated light showers about about the pastoral district and about central parts. Southeast to northeasterly winds.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-03-25T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-26T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-24T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-25T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers and thunderstorms about the agricultural area and south of the pastoral districts, showers possibly extending throughout the North West Pastoral district. Maximum temperatures above average, grading to below average in the northeast and about the coastal districts. Southeast to southwesterly winds extending throughout during the day, fresh at times about coastal districts during the afternoon and evening.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-03-26T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-27T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-25T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-26T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about the agricultural area and south of the pastoral districts. Possible thunderstorms about the pastoral and Flinders districts. Maximum temperatures below average to well below average about central districts. Southwest to southeasterly winds, fresh to strong about coastal districts.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="4" start-time-local="2026-03-27T00:00:00+10:30" end-time-local="2026-03-28T00:00:00+10:30" start-time-utc="2026-03-26T13:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-03-27T13:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Possible light showers about windward coasts and ranges. Maximum temperatures well below average. South to southeasterly winds, fresh about coastal districts.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Friday: less than 2 mm broadly about the agricultural areas, south of the Pastoral districts and the North West Pastoral district, possibly reaching 5mm about parts of the southern agricultural area. Isolated falls of 5 to 15 mm, mostly with thunderstorms.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
