<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-06-16T06:30:00Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-16T16:00:00+09:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-06-16T06:30:01Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-06-16T21:30:00Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-16T16:00:01+09:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-20T23:59:59+09:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-06-16T18:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-17T04:00:00+09:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-06-16T16:00:01+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-16T16:00:01+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-16T06:30:01Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-16T06:30:01Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A high pressure system centred over the Tasman Sea extends a ridge over eastern parts of SA. A low pressure system south of the Bight will remain slow-moving until later Thursday when it will move southeastwards. An associated cold front will move across SA during Wednesday followed by a second front later Thursday and Friday. A high pressure system will move across from the west over the weekend.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-06-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Areas of rain and showers, less likely in the far northeast and gradually clearing from the west. Showers re-developing about western coasts late afternoon and evening. Isolated thunderstorms in the west and possibly over central districts. Maximum temperatures below average in the far west but mostly near to above average elsewhere. Freshening northeast to northwesterly winds ahead of a westerly change moving over the west later.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-06-16T17:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-16T07:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Areas of rain and showers over western parts and the agricultural area, tending to isolated showers over the Flinders district and the south of the North East Pastoral district. Isolated thunderstorms in the west, possibly reaching western parts of Lower Eyre Peninsula and Kangaroo Island. Freshening north to northeasterly winds ahead of a westerly change moving over the far west later.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-06-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Rain and isolated thunderstorms becoming confined to the northeast early morning then slowly contracting eastwards. Showers re-developing across the West Coast district then gradually extending over remaining western and central agricultural districts during the day and reaching eastern agricultural districts in the evening. Isolated thunderstorms near western and southern coasts. Maximum temperatures near average about eastern border areas but below average elsewhere. Northwest to westerly winds, shifting west to southwesterly in the west. Strong at times near the coast.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-06-19T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-20T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-18T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-19T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about western districts and the agricultural area and isolated showers possible about the Flinders district and southern parts of the pastoral districts. Possible thunderstorms near southern coasts early. Maximum temperatures mostly below average. West to southwesterly winds gradually extending throughout. Fresh about the coast.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="4" start-time-local="2026-06-20T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-21T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-19T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-20T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Showers about the agricultural area, possibly reaching southern parts of the pastoral districts and far west. Showers contracting to coastal areas during the evening. Maximum temperatures below average. Southwest to southerly winds tending south to southeasterly later.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Saturday will be highly dependent on the movement of the low: generally 10 to 40 mm grading to 5 to 20 mm northeast of Pukatja/Ernabella to Broken Hill increasing to areas of 40 to 70 mm over parts of the North West Pastoral district, West Coast, Lower Eyre Peninsula, Kangaroo Island and the Mount Lofty Ranges districts.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
