<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<product version="1.7" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.bom.gov.au/schema/v1.7/product.xsd">
    <amoc>
        <source>
            <sender>Australian Government Bureau of Meteorology</sender>
            <region>South Australia</region>
            <office>SARO</office>
            <copyright>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/copyright.shtml</copyright>
            <disclaimer>http://www.bom.gov.au/other/disclaimer.shtml</disclaimer>
        </source>
        <identifier>IDS10033</identifier>
        <issue-time-utc>2026-06-14T18:30:00Z</issue-time-utc>
        <issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-15T04:00:00+09:30</issue-time-local>
        <sent-time>2026-06-14T18:30:03Z</sent-time>
        <expiry-time>2026-06-15T09:30:00Z</expiry-time>
        <validity-bgn-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-15T04:00:04+09:30</validity-bgn-time-local>
        <validity-end-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-18T23:59:59+09:30</validity-end-time-local>
        <next-routine-issue-time-utc>2026-06-15T06:30:00Z</next-routine-issue-time-utc>
        <next-routine-issue-time-local tz="CST">2026-06-15T16:00:00+09:30</next-routine-issue-time-local>
        <status>O</status>
        <service>WSP</service>
        <sub-service>FST</sub-service>
        <product-type>F</product-type>
        <phase>NEW</phase>
    </amoc>
    <forecast>
        <area aac="SA_FA001" description="South Australia" type="region">
            <forecast-period start-time-local="2026-06-15T04:00:04+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-15T04:00:04+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-14T18:30:04Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-14T18:30:04Z">
                <text type="synoptic_situation">A weak high pressure system to the east extends a ridge over SA. A northerly flow across South Australia will increase ahead of a slow-moving low pressure system that is expected to track along the SA coast this week.</text>
                <text type="warning_summary_footer">For latest warnings go to www.bom.gov.au, subscribe to RSS feeds, call 1300 659 210* or listen for warnings on relevant TV and radio broadcasts.</text>
                <text type="product_footer">* Calls to 1300 numbers cost around 27.5c incl. GST, higher from mobiles or public phones.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="0" start-time-local="2026-06-15T05:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-16T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-14T19:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-15T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Showers about the south of the North West Pastoral district and the West Coast, tending to patchy rain and extending into central and southeastern districts during the day. Possible thunderstorms about the west. Maximum temperatures near average grading to above average in the north. North to northeasterly winds ahead of a west to southwesterly change moving across the far west late in the evening.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="1" start-time-local="2026-06-16T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-17T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-15T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-16T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Areas of rain and isolated thunderstorms over western parts and the southern agricultural area, tending to isolated showers over the Flinders district and the south of the North East Pastoral district. Maximum temperatures near to above average. Freshening northerly winds ahead of a westerly change moving over the far west later.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="2" start-time-local="2026-06-17T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-18T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-16T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-17T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">Areas of rain and isolated thunderstorms, less likely in the far northeast and clearing from the far west. Maximum temperatures above average lowering to slightly below average in the far west. Northeast to northwesterly winds.</text>
            </forecast-period>
            <forecast-period index="3" start-time-local="2026-06-18T00:00:00+09:30" end-time-local="2026-06-19T00:00:00+09:30" start-time-utc="2026-06-17T14:30:00Z" end-time-utc="2026-06-18T14:30:00Z">
                <text type="forecast">
                    <p>Rain and isolated thunderstorms clearing to the east early morning. Showers redeveloping across the West Coast, extending over remaining western and central agricultural districts later in the day. Maximum temperatures near to slightly above average in the east, lowering to below average in the west. Northwesterly winds tending west to southwesterly in the west.</p>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Cumulative rainfall totals to the end of Thursday are highly dependent on the movement of this week's low pressure system: Generally 10 to 40 mm grading to 2 to 10 mm northeast of about Pukatja/Ernabella to Yunta, increasing to areas of 40 to 70 mm over the West Coast and Lower Eyre Peninsula, and possibly about Kangaroo Island. Isolated higher totals in excess of 70 mm are likely possible about western Eyre Peninsula.</p>
                </text>
            </forecast-period>
        </area>
    </forecast>
</product>
